Was that good?
Let's see...
Yeah.
It's all blurry.
Rin-chan, Kouki, stand side by side!
Okay!
Kouki-kun!
I'm taking it!
Now, let's take a picture of you with Rin-chan.
No, it's fine.
That won't do!
She'll be all grown up before you know it.
You need to make memories while you still can.
Right.
Daikichi-san, you're too tense!
Jeez!
Rin, how many times do I have to tell you not to wander around alone?
Okay.
You're a big girl now, so shape up!
Don't give me that!
Daikichi, can we get this as a snack?
A snack?!
Well, it looks tasty.
Haven't you ever eaten cereal before?
Nope.
Is it too much for me?
I don't mind buying it,
but it's something you eat for breakfast.
Is it okay to eat sweets with your meal?
How can I put this? It looks like sweets,
but you can have it for breakfast.
You add milk to it.
Why don't you have that for breakfast tomorrow?
Yeah, I'll do that.
Will you have some too, Daikichi?
No, that's not enough for me.
Put the cereal in here.
Daikichi, you're bad at this.
My hands are too dry.
You're like an old man.
I'm not an old man yet!
Okay, let's see you do it then.
Daikichi, there are cherry blossoms over there, so let's go this way.
All right.
They're blooming everywhere!
That's because of the warm weather.
It's huge!
It's in full bloom.
Since you just got into grade school,
how about we plant something to commemorate it?
Commemorate?
It's like making a memory.
Year after year, both you and the tree will grow.
I see.
I have a tree too.
Near our house?
Back in my hometown.
When I was born, my parents planted a fragrant olive tree,
and for Kazumi, they planted a sweet olive tree.
Is a fragnant olive tree the one that smells nice?
Yeah.
I don't know what a sweet olive tree is, though.
The sweet olive tree is pretty plain when it comes to flowers or fragrance.
She'd rip the flowers off my tree while yelling,
"It's not fair that only yours smells good!"
When I said I'd be willing to trade,
she said, "I don't need a second-hand tree!"
Wait, that's sort of a bad memory, so why am I trying to do the same for her?
A tree with nice flowers would be better, right?
And we can watch it grow.
I'd like a loquat!
A loquat?
Yeah! A loquat!
I have a few loquat seeds.
You're going to plant them?
I can eat as many loquats as I want!
Only if you take good care of it.
I was thinking of planting a tree that's as tall as you.
So we can't get a loquat?
It grows a lot slower than other plants like the morning glory.
You know the proverb?
"Peaches and chestnuts take three years..."
TL Note: This proverb basically means, it takes time to see the results of hard work.
"...and eight years for persimmons!"
As expected of Grandpa's kid.
What about loquats?
I don't know,
but what are you going to do if it takes ten years or so?
I can wait.
After that, you'll be more interested in fancy sweets and food.
I can't even imagine.
Daikichi! Hurry up!
If we don't hurry, I'll have to wait even longer to eat them!
Yeah, yeah.
Is this enough?
Yeah. If you dig too deep, the shoot won't be able to grow out.
I see.
You really are Grandpa's kid.
I hope it starts growing soon!
Yeah.
Rin, do you know about ninjas?
Yeah. Kouki-kun wants to become one.
It's said that a ninja would jump over a hemp plant every day.
As the tree would keep getting bigger,
the ninja would be able to jump great heights.
Want to try the same thing with this loquat?
I do!
Something like that.
Like that?
Yeah.
Say, how tall does a loquat tree grow?
As big as this house?
Well, I guess so.
Let's go back inside now.
Ten times more!
I wonder if it'll take root by tomorrow.
Tomorrow would be too soon.
You have all your stuff?
My timetable.
I'm supposed to get someone from home to check it.
Sounds annoying.
I don't remember doing all this as a kid.
It's true.
It says, "Please confirm."
A fire?
Sounds like a police car.
An accident, then?
Not sure.
Daikichi, attach this whistle to my bag.
Rin.
If a stranger starts talking to you, you need to blow into this really hard.
I know.
And any house is fine, so just go and hide.
Yeah.
Even a shop will do!
Okay!
Rin! What about school?
Daikichi, wake up quick!
I'm going to be late!
Okay.
Thank you for the food.
Thank you for the food!
You need to add milk.
Can I have a little without milk?
Sure.
Pet dogs eat this kind of stuff, right?
They eat dog food!
It's made for dogs.
Really?
Yeah!
People shouldn't eat food made for dogs.
Don't look so disappointed about that.
Is it good?
Yeah, it's delicious.
Rice balls are still number one, though.
You sure like rice balls, huh?
Daikichi, your phone.
I'll get it.
G-Good morning!
I'm sorry. Kouki was all fired up, and he dashed out of the house!
Not a problem.
We're fine here.
Rin-chan!
Right.
Kouki-kun is here!
Rin-chan!
He's here.
Yo.
Kouki-kun, you've got burrs stuck to your clothes!
What kind of animal path did you take to get here?
I'm not an animal!
And what's with your hair?
Rin, go get a comb.
Okay!
Your bag is all scratched!
You went around scraping that stick against people's walls, didn't you?
Are you an esper?!
You don't need to be one to figure that out!
Is that something you used to do too?
Rin, go get ready!
Okay!
What's with that look?
I'm off!
Hang on for a second!
I'll see you off...
What's wrong?!
Kouki-kun! You're not supposed to blow the whistle for no reason!
Kouki-kun!
Hey!
Stop blowing that whistle!
People won't come help even if something does happen!
You understand?
Yeah.
Go on, then.
We're off!
Watch out for cars!
Okay!
Kouki-kun!
Let's go this way!
We're not supposed to stray from this route.
It's not really straying. This is a shortcut!
Ninjas take these kinds of paths!
Jeez.
It's all wavy!
Right?
Kouki-kun, you're taking too long!
It defeats the point of taking a shortcut!
That's not what you're supposed to do!
Kouki-kun!
He's an incorrigible kid.
I know, right?
Well, it happens.
Pretty much all boys are like that.
Daikichi!
Ninja training should be limited to jumping over the loquat.
Right?
Hey, that loquat tree is a commemoration for starting grade school, right?
Yeah.
Your fragrant olive tree was a commemoration for your birth, so it's a bit different.
I guess I don't have a fragrant olive tree like that.
You're way too smart.
I wonder if her mother planted a tree or anything.
Maybe there's one at Grandpa's place.
Oh, yeah. Grandpa might have.
You don't know if he did, right?
Yeah.
Grandpa's not around anymore, either.
If I don't know, no one else would, would they?
I shouldn't have told her about the fragrant olive tree.
Daikichi, you've got your elbows on the table again!
Right! Sorry.
Damn it.
I thought we wouldn't have to see each other again.
I thought the same thing.
This picture is from her entrance ceremony.
Thank you.
A tree for Rin?
Actually, there is one!
There is?
Well, I think there is.
Why are you so unsure?
Souichi-san was the one who planted it.
Grandpa did?
I'd like to replant that tree at my place.
What kind of tree is it?
It's a small one.
Do you know what type it is
and where it's planted?
Let's see... It's pretty small,
and the branches are thin.
It's here.
You are a manga artist, aren't you?
My work doesn't consist of drawing maps!
Which way is north?
North?
Well, the sun rises in the west, so-
That's wrong! It's the opposite!
Forget about the map.
Just write down where it is around the house.
I see. That'll work.
Well then, I have work to do, so I'll be leaving now.
Thank you for the food.
Sorry for disturbing you when you're busy.
I wonder if my tree is there.
I'm sure Grandpa planted something for you, Rin-chan.
I have a feeling about it.
Even if he didn't,
you can plant another one, separate from your grade school one.
A tree for when you're six, okay?
Okay.
You want to see Daikichi's tree?
Yeah, I do!
It's big!
Yeah, because Daikichi is thirty years old.
Daikichi has grown up too!
It's a fragrant olive, right?
Yes. How do you know that?
Daikichi told me.
This one is Kazumi's tree.
The sweet olive?
Yes.
You remember there was big tree in the garden behind Grandpa's house?
Yeah, what about it?
That's my tree, a sweet olive.
Huh? This tree...
Grandpa planted it when I was born.
You have the same tree as Kazumi-onee-chan?
That's right.
I always compared our heights as a kid.
I liked it so much that I decided to do the same here.
Was that a sweet olive tree?
Did Daikichi compare his height to the tree too?
Of course!
Long before the day we first met...
Daikichi, is that...
It has the same leaves!
It's a six-year-old fragrant olive.
The same as mine.
All done.
Oh, no!
What's wrong?
I can't jump over this one.
I don't think I can, either.
We didn't even know about Rin half a year ago.
I know.
Daikichi, we're going to miss the train!
Okay!
Bye, then.
I'll see you off.
Long before the day we first met,
you were in the same flow of life as me.
Daikichi!
What's wrong?!
What happened?!
There's a weird old guy outside!
Kouki-kun.
You're wrong. That person-
What?!
Daikichi, you're wrong.
Where is he?!
Jeez, just listen to me, both of you!
That's Matsui-san, our neighbor!
Don't call him a weird old man!
I'm really sorry.
I'm... sor... ry.
I'm at fault too. I called out to them all of a sudden and probably startled them.
Sorry about that.
Not at all. He was very rude to you.
Well, take care.
We're off!
Thank you.
When you ran away, you dragged Rin along.
But he made a mistake.
As long as Kouki is with you, I feel a bit at ease.
Just a bit?
Yeah, just a bit!
You're still a little brat.
I'm not little!
We're going to be late.